Pierre-Stéphane Voltaire

psvoltaire96@gmail.com | +1(905)-616-0236 | psvoltaire.ca | linkedin.com/in/pierre-stephane-voltaire github.com/PierreStephaneVoltaire

Summary

Software Engineer with 7 years of experience developing frontend and backend services and automating cloud infrastructure. Skilled in building reliable CI/CD pipelines, provisioning infrastructure with Terraform, CloudFormation, and AWS CDK, and developing backend services in Node.js, Python, Golang, and Java. Experienced with AWS, container orchestration using Kubernetes and ECS, and containerization with Docker.

Experience

Senior Platform Engineer, Mitsubishi UFJ Financial Group Investor Service – Toronto, ON

Mar 2021 - Present

- ullet Developed a FastAPI (Python) GitLab backup solution that protects \sim 1000 repositories against extended outages and accidental deletions, with deployment handled through ArgoCD and Kustomize for flexible environment configuration.
- Implemented and managed automated CI/CD pipelines, drastically cutting production deployment time from 4 hours to 15 minutes using GitLab CI, CodeDeploy, Python, bash and Powershell
- Developed secure and efficient processes and tools for managing secrets and injecting application configurations using Jenkins and Lambda functions in Python and Node.js.
- Supported, debugged, and maintained Java, Python, and Dotnet applications, playing a key role in restoring critical systems and preventing future outages.
- Migrated 6 legacy Maven and Dotnet applications to AWS within 2 years, provisioning cloud-native resources, optimizing system performance and automating build, test, and deployment processes

FullStack Developer, Airborne App – Oakville, ON

Aug 2020 - Mar 2021

- Developed features on existing Golang services that interact with multiple AWS services
- Integrated user-facing components on frontend apps with React, TypeScript, and SASS, improving overall user experience and app performance
- Developed an ephemeral testing environment pipeline using GitHub actions, terraform and S3, accelerating frontend validation processes and streamlining collaboration between developers, product owners, and designers within 6 months

FullStack Developer, EllisDon - Mississauga, ON

May 2019 - Apr 2020

- Developed and maintained services using ReactJS, Spring Boot (Java), Express (Node.js), NestJS (TypeScript), and MongoDB. Ensured seamless feature integration, bug resolution, and codebase enhancements for improved maintainability.
- Optimized project maintainability through automated CI pipelines for unit testing and code linting

Skills

Languages and Frameworks: Java, TypeScript, JavaScript, Golang, Python, Bash, Powershell,Sql, Spring Boot, Flask, Gin, Vue.js, Angular, ReactJS

Infrastructure, Monitoring & CI/CD: Terraform, Terragrunt, AWS CDK, Cloudformation, CodeDeploy, CodePipeline, CodeBuild, CircleCI, GitHub Actions, Jenkins, GitLab CI, ArgoCD, Datadog

Containerization & Orchestration: Docker, Podman, Docker Compose, Helm, ECS, Fargate, Kubernetes

Education

Sheridan College, Bachelor of Computer Science - Mobile Computing **Sheridan College**, Computer Systems Technician – Software Engineering

Sept 2016 – Apr 2020

Sept 2014 - Aug 2016